Look up in the sky!
Superman Returns is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Bryan Singer.
Superman returns to discover his 5-year absence has allowed Lex Luthor to walk free,
and that those he was closest to felt abandoned and have moved on.
Luthor plots his ultimate revenge that could see millions killed and change the face
of the planet forever, as well as ridding himself of the Man of Steel.
Clark Kent / Superman, played by Brandon Routh.
Lois Lane, played by Kate Bosworth.
Lex Luthor, played by Kevin Spacey.
Richard White, played by James Marsden.
Kitty Kowalski, played by Parker Posey.
Perry White, played by Frank Langella.
Superman Returns is a 2006 American superhero film
based on the DC Comics character Superman.
The film was directed by Bryan Singer, and written by Michael Dougherty and
Dan Harris from a story by Singer, Dougherty and Harris.
It serves as an homage sequel to Superman (1978) and Superman II (1980), ignoring the events of
Superman III (1983), Supergirl (1984), and Superman IV: The Quest for Peace (1987).
The film stars Brandon Routh as Superman, Kate Bosworth as Lois Lane and Kevin Spacey as Lex Luthor,
with James Marsden, Frank Langella, Eva Marie Saint and Parker Posey in supporting roles.
In the film, Superman returns to Earth after five years and discovers that his love interest Lois Lane has moved
on from him and that his archenemy Lex Luthor is planning to kill him and reshape North America.
After a series of unsuccessful projects to resurrect Superman following the
critical and financial failure of The Quest for Peace, Warner Bros.
Pictures hired Singer to direct Superman Returns in July 2004.
The majority of principal photography took place at Fox Studios Australia, Sydney while the visual effects sequences were handled by a number of studios, including Sony
Pictures Imageworks, Rhythm & Hues Studios (R&H), Framestore CFC, Rising Sun Pictures and The Orphanage; filming began in March 2005 and ended in November.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its visual effects,
storyline and Singer's direction, but criticized its screenplay and runtime.
While the film was one of the biggest films of the year, earning $391.1 million on a budget of
$204–223 million and becoming the ninth highest-grossing film of 2006, Warner Bros.
was disappointed with the worldwide box office return and
cancelled a sequel for release in 2009.
The Superman film series was rebooted in 2013 with Man of Steel,
directed by Zack Snyder and starring Henry Cavill as Superman.
Routh later reprised his role as Superman in the 2019
Arrowverse crossover "Crisis on Infinite Earths".
The film explores themes of saving the world, superhero,
invulnerability, based on comic, sequel.
The tone is thought_provoking.